# **MERALDO ANTONIO**

Email: meraldo.antonio@gmail.com Phone: (+65) 9865 4378 Nationality: Singaporean

An aspiring data scientist with two years of analytics experience. Experienced at visualizing data using Tableau and Plotly/Dash, training and deploying state-of-the-art NLP models using PyTorch and analyzing big data using Python, Spark/Scala and Hadoop.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Al Singapore, Singapore

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

## Al Apprentice

• Working with a corporate client to build, train and deploy a chatbot using deep learning technologies (PyTorch implementation of BiDAF, ELMo and BERT)

#### Datarama, Singapore

Aug 2017 - Feb 2019

#### Senior Analyst

- Led more than 100 complex due diligence investigations across Southeast Asia
- Developed a project and fee-tracking dashboard that led to 30% operational improvement
- Built interactive Tableau visualizations that were published in Datarama's reports and website
- · Contributed to the technical development of Datarama's Al-powered risk analysis platform

#### Blackpeak Group, Singapore

Feb 2016 – Jul 2017

### Senior Associate

- Performed more than 100 due diligence and political risk analyses across Southeast Asia
- Provided risk advisory to Blackpeak clients including multinational companies, investment banks and PE funds

## **Lux Research,** Singapore and Boston (USA)

Jul 2013 - Feb 2016

#### Research Associate

- Acted as a subject matter expert on the field of green chemicals
- Advised senior executives from Fortune 500 companies on emerging green technology trends
- Represented Lux Research in delivering speeches in international conferences as well as speaking to the press

#### **BASF,** Ludwigshafen (Germany)

Jul 2012 - Apr 2013

## Research Intern

- Developed a novel formaldehyde-free microencapsulation method
- Wrote a thesis on the project that led to a master's degree with High Distinction

## **EDUCATION**

## **Georgia Institute of Technology**

May 2018 – Aug 2020 (expected)

M.Sc. in Analytics (specialization in Computational Data Analytics)

- Current GPA of 4.00 out of 4.00
- Relevant courses: Simulation and Modeling and Big Data in Healthcare

#### National University of Singapore and Technical University of Munich

Aug 2011 – Apr 2013

Joint M.Sc. in Industrial Chemistry

- GPA 4.64 out of 5.00 (High Distinction)
- Obtained a full scholarship from BASF

#### **Nanyang Technological University**

Aug 2007 – Jun 2011

B.Sc. in Chemistry and Biological Chemistry

- GPA 4.76 out of 5.00 (First Class Honours)
- Dean's List for the academic years 2008/2009 and 2009/201

# SKILLS

# **Data Analytics and Machine Learning**

- Python (including Pandas, Plotly/Dash, XGBoost, Scikit-learn): advanced
- Pytorch: intermediate
- NLP (libraries such as NLTK as well as implementation of models such as BiDAF and ELMo): intermediate
- Tensorflow/Keras: intermediate
- Spark (including MLlib and GraphX) in Scala/PySpark: intermediate
- Hadoop (Sqoop, Pig, Hive, Ambari): intermediate
- Tableau (including dashboards): intermediate
- SQL: advancedDocker: beginner

# Languages

Indonesian: nativeEnglish: fluentSpanish: fluent

Chinese: intermediateFrench: intermediate

# **PROFILES**

• LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/meraldo

• GitHub: github.com/meraldoantonio

• Personal website: meraldoantonio.github.io/about

• Medium: medium.com/@meraldo.antonio

• Tableau public: public.tableau.com/profile/meraldo.antonio